# Jimmy Lei Ba

# jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a fourth year PhD student researching deep neural networks. In particular, my focus is on developing attention-based deep learning models and stochastic optimization algorithms. Also, I am broadly interested in questions related to computational cognitive science, artificial intelligence and Bayesian statistics.

#### **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy, Electrical & Computer Engineering
University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

Master of Applied Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering
University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

Bachelor of Applied Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering
University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

2013 - Present
2011 - 2013
2017 - 2011

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

### Publications in refereed proceedings:

- **Ba, J.**, Grosse, R. and Martens, J., (2017), "Distributed Second-Order Optimization using Kronecker-factored Approximation", *Proceedings of the 2017 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'17)*
- **Ba, J.**, Kiros, J. R. and Hinton, G., (2016), "Layer Normalization", *Neural Information Processing System Deep Learning Symposium 2017*
- **Ba, J.**, Hinton, G., Mnih, V., Leibo, J. and Ionescu, C., (2016), "Using Fast Weight to Attend to the Recent Past", *Advances in the 2016 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'16)*
- Kraus, O., **Ba, J.** and Frey, B., (2016), "Classifying Microscopy Images Using Convolutional Multiple Instance Learning", *Bioinformatics* 32(12), 52-59
- Mansim, E., Parisotto, E., Ba, J. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2016), "Generating Images From Captions with Attention", Proceedings of the 2016 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'16)
- Parisotto, E., Ba, J. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2016), "Actor-Mimic: Deep Multitask and Transfer Reinforcement Learning", Proceedings of the 2016 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'16)
- **Ba, J.**, Grosse, R., Salakhutdinov, R. and Frey, B., (2015), "Learning Wake-Sleep Recurrent Attention Models", *Advances in the 2015 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'15)*
- **Ba, J.**, Swersky, K., Fidler, S. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2015), "Predicting Deep Zero-Shot Convolutional Neural Networks using Textual Descriptions", *Proceedings of 2015 International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV'15)*,
- Xu, K., Ba, J., Kiros, R., Cho, K., Courville, A., Salakhutdinov, R., Zemel, R. and Bengio, Y., (2015), "Show, Attend and Tell: Neural Image Caption Generation with Visual Attention", *Proceedings of 2015 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML'15)*
- Kingma D., **Ba, J.**, (2015), "Adam: A Method for Stochastic Optimization", *Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'15)*

# Jimmy Lei Ba

# jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

- **Ba, J.,** Mnih, V. and Kavukcuoglu K., (2015), "Multiple Object Recognition with Visual Attention", *Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'15)*
- **Ba, J.,** Xiong and H, Frey, B., (2014), "Making Dropout Invariant to Transformations of Activation Functions and Inputs", *Advances in the 2014 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'14) deep learning workshop*
- **Ba, J.** and Caruana, R., (2014), "Do deep nets really need to be deep?", *Advances in the 2014 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'14)*
- **Ba, J.** and Frey, B., (2013), "Adaptive Dropout for Training Deep Neural Networks", *Advances in the 2013 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'13)*

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

## Facebook Graduate Student Fellowship

2016 - Present

University of Toronto 2009 – Present

- Electrical and Computer Engineering Outstanding Student Award (2009 2011)
- University of Toronto Excellent Award in the Natural Science and Engineering (2009 2010)
- Dean's Honours List
- Collage of Physics and Engineering Science Dean's Scholarship (2007 2008)

#### Others

• Canadian Euclid Mathematic Competition, Special Award (2007)

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Course intructor and coordinator, University of Toronto	2017
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Head TA and guest lecturer, University of Toronto	2016
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Guest lecturer on inference algorithms and message-passing, University of Toronto	2015
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Head TA, designed two new assignments, 7 weeks of tutorial sessions, University of Toronto	2015
CSC2523 Deep Learning in Computer Vision Guest lecturer on neural programming, University of Toronto	2015
CSC321 Introduction to Neural Networks and Machine Learning Guest lectuer on probability theory and inference algorithms, University of Toronto	2014
CSC321 Introduction to Neural Networks and Machine Learning Tutorial TA, 4 weeks of tutorial sessions and lecture assistant, University of Toronto	2014

# Jimmy Lei Ba

jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

ECE1510/CSC2535 Advanced Inference Algorithms/Advanced Machine Learning Guest lecturer on deep learning, University of Toronto	2014
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Guest lecturer on neural netowrks and deep learning, University of Toronto	2013
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Tutorial TA, 6 weeks of tutorial sessions, University of Toronto	2013
WORK EXPERIENCE, TEAM WORK, AND COMMUNICATION	
Research Intern Google Deepmind, London, England	2014
Research Intern	2013
Microsoft Research, Redmond, Washington	
Software Development Engineer Sybase iAnywhere Inc., Waterloo, Ontario	2009
INDEPENDENT RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT	
Machine Learning Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science, University of Toronto Supervisor: Geoffrey Hinton, Brendan Frey & Ruslan Salakhutdinov	2014 – Present
Machine Learning and Computer Vision Research Assistant, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Toronto Supervisor: Brendan Frey	2011 – 2013
Signal Processing and Multimedia Wearable Computing Research Assistant, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Toronto Supervisor: Steve Mann	2010